(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone, welcome
back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're gonna
be bringing you a great
lesson that's talking
about a bank robbery.
- Yes, and this is an
important lesson for all
of our, you know, future
bank robbers out there.
- Yeah, we are going
to teach you some words
that you would use for
planning a bank robbery,
but you can apply them to
other situations, hopefully not.
- Yeah, I hope you apply
them to other situations.
- Hopefully you won't rob a bank,
we don't want to be responsible
for any crimes, you can commit.
- Yes, yep.
- All right, so why
don't we start by looking
at some of the vocabulary
in vocabulary preview?
- Very cabaret-y preview.
- We have one word
for you today that you'll
hear in the dialogue
and it is filling in.
- Filling in, filling in.
- So to fill in for somebody, right?
- Yeah.
- That means that you are replacing them.
- Yes, so if Marco can't host the
show today, maybe Danny will fill in.
- Okay, so to take the place of someone.
- Exactly. - All right.
- Okay, so now let's
listen to our dialogue, let's
listen to this bank robbery,
and let's see what happens.
(upbeat music)
- All right, so this is
what we're going to do.
I've carefully mapped this
out, so don't screw it up.
Mr. Rabbit, you and Mr. Fox will go
into the bank wearing these uniforms.
We've managed to get
replicas of the one the
guards wear for when
they pick up the money.
- Got it.
- No problem, boss.
When you get inside, tell
them that you're filling in
for Carl and Tom and say that
they're on another route today.
Don't lose your cool, just act natural.
- What did they want to call him confirm?
- You let him.
- What?
- Don't worry, we have the phone's tapped,
so the call will be patched through to me,
and I'll pretend to be
the transport company.
- Uh huh, you're so clever, boss.
- Okay, shut up.
Only take as much money
as you can fit in these bags.
Don't get greedy, are you ready?
Let's go.
(upbeat music)
- Well, it sounds like a
pretty interesting plan.
- It does sound like a
plan, do you think it'll work?
- I don't know, I guess we'll have to,
maybe talk a little bit about that later.
- Okay, let's take a look at the language
that we saw in language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- Okay, we heard five really
great words in this dialogue
that I'd like to look at
now in language takeaway.
So let's go to the first one.
Now we heard the boss say that
they got replicas of the uniforms.
- Right, replicas.
- Replicas.
- So this is really easy.
- It's something that's
a replica is a copy.
- Exactly.
- So for example, in Las Vegas, there's
a replica of the Eiffel Tower of Paris.
- Yes, actually I lived in a small city
where there was also a
replica of the Eiffel Tower.
- Really?
- Yeah, in France, that was kind of weird.
(laughing)
- Well, there are a lot of
replicas even now on the street,
maybe you can see replica watches
that supposedly are Rolex, but they're not.
And many, many other things, so copies.
- Yes, not the real
thing, not the real thing.
- All right, so let's take a
look at the next word, tapped.
- We have the phones tapped.
- We have the phones tapped, tapped.
So if you tap someone's phone, you
do something to the telephone line
so that you can hear
their conversation, right?
- Right, and actually the
police do this sometimes, right?
- Right, you see in movies all the time.
- Yeah, yeah, you connect a wire to the
phone so you can listen to the conversation.
- Exactly, so you tap the telephone line.
So in our dialogue, they
tapped the bank's phone, right?
You know, he said if they make a call, he
will patch the call through to him, right?
- So patch through.
- Yeah, patch a call through.
- Patch through.
Now we still use this today,
like if you call an office,
right, and you say, oh, can
you patch me through to Carol?
- Yes, right.
- So can you connect
me to another phone line?
- Connect me, right?
All right, now let's take a
look at our next words, clever.
- Yes, the boss is very clever.
- The boss is very clever.
- All right, so if you're
clever, you're smart.
- Yep.
- You're really smart.
- Right, simple, so the boss is
quite clever and this is a clever plan.
- Clever plan, exactly.
Now, let's take a look at our last word.
Don't be greedy, greedy, greedy.
- To be greedy is a bad thing.
- Right, you want everything.
- You want everything for you?
- Yes. - You don't share.
- Yes.
- So like at lunch today,
when you had that cake.
(laughing)
- And I didn't share.
- I was very greedy.
(laughing)
- Yes, with food, I am greedy.
- All right.
So these are some great
words and I think, you know,
if we listen to the dialogue
another time, a little bit more slowly,
we'll be able to hear
them a little bit better.
(upbeat music)
- All right, so this is
what we're going to do.
I've carefully mapped this
out, so don't screw it up.
Mr. Rabbit, you and Mr. Fox will go
into the bank, wearing these uniforms.
We've managed to get replicas of the one
the guards wear when they pick up the money.
- Got it.
- No problem, boss.
When you get inside, tell
them that you're filling in
for Carl and Tom, and say that
they're on another route today.
Don't lose your cool.
Just act natural.
- What if they want a call and conform?
- You let him.
- What?
- Don't worry.
We have the phones tapped, so
the call will be patched through
to me, and I'll pretend to
be the transport company.
- You're so clever, boss.
- Okay, shut up.
Only take as much money
as you can fit into these bags.
Don't get greedy.
Are you ready?
Let's go.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so now we understand these words
that we talked about in language takeaway.
So now let's take a look at some of these
great phrases in low-end seat builder.
- Fluency builder.
- We've got three phrases
for you here, and these are
all phrases you might use
when you're planning something.
So the first one mapped out.
- I've carefully mapped this out.
- Mapped out.
- To map out.
So when you map something
out, what do you do?
- Well, you literally create a plan.
You draw a map of what you're going to do.
- So here, is it only for travel or?
- No, no, no, no, it's like, for example,
if we're starting a new project in the
company, you can map out the project,
what you're going to do this
month, next month, so it's a plan.
- So you draw every step in the plan.
- Every step, right?
- So you said, well, I've mapped
out this plan for a new project.
- Okay, interesting word.
I think we should hear some
examples of how it's used.
- Example one.
So I have the future all mapped out.
- Well, you'll get a job
as a waiter, then we'll get
married, and two years
later, we'll start having kids.
- Example two.
- We're mapping out the
marketing plan at the meeting today.
- Example three.
- Okay, I've mapped out our trip,
and it should take about 10 hours.
- All right, so mapped
out really, really clear now.
- Mm-hmm.
- Let's take a look at our next word.
- All right, so if you've mapped out
a plan, you don't want to screw it up.
- Right, screw it up,
screw it up, or screw up.
- Yep.
- So just screw something up means
that you made a mistake on something.
- Or you did something wrong.
- You did it wrong.
- Yep.
- Okay, so for example,
if I'm taking an exam,
and I make a mistake, I
screwed up on the exam.
- Exactly.
- Or for example here, when we're
recording, Marco and I make mistakes a lot.
- Maybe more me than
Marco and I always screw up.
- Yeah.
- Exactly, so to make a mistake, it's a
really informal word, but very, very common.
- Yeah, and you know, it sounds really,
really natural when people use this.
- All right, so now let's
take a look at our last word.
- Lose your cool.
- Don't lose your cool.
- So what is this to lose your cool?
It's a weird expression.
- It's a weird expression.
Why don't we just give you an example
of a person that loses his or her cool?
- What do you mean you're not ready to go?
It's time to go.
We have to go now, boning at all.
We were supposed to leave.
Puneeta, now we're sitting here again.
I'm gonna wait for you.
Boning him.
- Okay, so basically you lose your temper.
You become irritated.
- You lose control of your emotions.
- Right.
- So Marco, when you lose your
cool, is it always that you get angry?
You don't always get angry.
Maybe you get irritated or
impatient or even nervous?
- Nervous.
- Yeah, right.
So basically you're not in
control of your emotions.
- Yeah.
- Okay, so we've looked at a lot of
great phrases, a lot of great words.
So we can listen to our
dialogue now for the third time
and then we'll come back and talk
about this bank robbery business.
(upbeat music)
- All right, so this is
what we're gonna do.
I've carefully mapped this
out, so don't screw it up.
Mr. Rabbit, you and Mr. Fox will go
into the bank wearing these uniforms.
We've managed to get
replicas of the one the
guards wear for when
they pick up the money.
- Got it.
- No problem, boss.
When you get inside, tell
them that you're filling in
for Carl and Tom and say that
they're on another route today.
Don't lose your cool.
Just act natural.
- What did they wanna call and confirm?
- You let him.
- What?
- Don't worry, we have the phones tapped.
So the car will be patched through to me
and I'll pretend to be
the transport company.
- Uh-huh, you're so clever, boss.
- Okay, shut up.
Only take as much money
as you can fit in these bags.
Don't get greedy.
Are you ready?
Let's go.
(upbeat music)
- So there's a lot of
movies about bank
robberies, but obviously
they happen in real life.
So this dialogue is actually
based on real events, right?
- Yeah, this actually
happened in real life.
And so it's actually a very creative
and nonviolent way of robbing a bank.
- Okay, so what happens?
- Basically this guy went to a bank
dressed up as one of those security guards
that transport the money from
the bank to another safe place.
He had fake credentials
or replica credentials.
- So fake ID.
- Yeah, he had a replica of the uniform.
- Wow.
- And he walked in, he took all these bags,
with him and his partner
and they took him to the truck
and drove off and the bank didn't
realize that they had been robbed.
They thought it was a routine thing.
Three or four hours later, the
real security guard shows up.
They were long gone and
they still can't find them.
- Really?
So a very clever plan.
- Very clever and very effective, I think.
They stole over half a million dollars.
- Okay, well guys, don't try this at home.
- Don't try this at home,
but real life real English, right?
- Exactly.
- Okay, so come to our
website, leave your questions
and comments, tell us what you
think will happen with these guys.
Do you think they'll be successful?
Do you think they'll get caught?
- Yeah, they might end up in jail.
- Maybe somebody will lose their
cool and then get caught, right?
- Well, thanks for listening, guys.
And until next time, goodbye.
(upbeat music)